You've seen how regularization can help
现在你应该已经知道(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
prevent overfitting, but how
算法正则化可以有效地防止过拟合
does it affect the bias and
但正则化跟算法的偏差和方差
variance of a learning algorithm?
又有什么关系呢？
In this video, I like to
在这段视频中
go deeper into the issue
我想更深入地
of bias and variance, and
探讨一下偏差和方差的问题
talk about how it interacts
讨论一下两者之间
with, and is effected by,
是如何相互影响的
the regularization of your learning algorithm.
以及和算法的正则化之间的相互关系
Suppose we're fitting a high
假如我们要对这样一个
order polynomial like that shown
高阶的多项式
here, but to prevent
进行拟合
overfitting, we're going to
为了防止过拟合现象
use regularization, like that shown
我们要使用如幻灯片所示的正则化
here, so we have this regularization
因此我们试图通过这样一个正则化项
term to try to
来让参数的值
keep the values of the parameters small.
尽可能小
And as usual, the regularization sums
正则化项的求和范围
from j equals 1 to
照例取为j等于1到m
m rather than j equals 0
而非j等于0到m
to m.  Let's consider three cases.
然后我们来分析以下三种情形
The first is the case of
第一种情形是
a very large value of the
正则化参数lambda
regularization parameter lambda, such
取一个比较大的值
as if lambda were
比如lambda的值
equal to 10,000s of huge value.
取为10000甚至更大
In this
在这种情况下
case, all of these
所有这些参数
parameters, theta 1, theta 2,
包括theta1 theta2
theta 3 and so on will
theta3 等等
be heavily penalized and
将被大大惩罚
so, what ends up with most
其结果是
of these parameter values being close
这些参数的值
to 0 and the hypothesis will be
将近似等于0
roughly h or x
并且假设模型
just equal or approximately equal
h(x)的值将等于或者近似等于
to theta 0, and so we
theta0的值
end up a hypothesis that more
因此我们最终得到的假设函数
or less looks like that. This is more or
应该是这个样子
less a flat, constant straight line.
近似是一条平滑的直线
And so this hypothesis has high
因此这个假设处于高偏差
bias and a value underfits this data set.
对数据集欠拟合
So the horizontal straight
因此这条水平直线
line is just not a very
对这个数据集来讲
good model for this data set.
不是一个好的假设模型
At the other extreme beam is if we have
与之对应的另一种情况是
a very small value of
如果我们的lambda值很小
lambda, such as if lambda
比如说lambda的值
were equal to 0.
等于0的时候
In that case, given that we're
在这种情况下
fitting a high order polynomial,
如果我们要拟合一个高阶多项式的话
this is a
那么此时我们通常会处于
usual overfitting setting.
过拟合的情况
In that case, given that we're
在这种情况时
fitting a high order polynomial,
在拟合一个高阶多项式时
basically without regularization or with
如果没有进行正则化
very minimal regularization, we end
或者正则化程度很微小的话
up with our usual high variance, overfitting
我们通常会得到高方差和过拟合的结果
setting, because basically if lambda is
因为通常来说
equal to zero, we are just
lambda的值等于0
fitting with our regularization so
相当于没有正则化项
that overfits the hypothesis
因此是过拟合假设
and is only if we have some
只有当我们取一个中间大小的
intermediate value of lambda that is neither too large nor too small that we end up with parameters theta
既不大也不小的lambda值时
that we end up that give us a reasonable
我们才会得到一组合理的
fit to this data.
对数据刚好拟合的theta参数值
So how can we automatically
那么我们应该怎样
choose a good value
自动地选择出一个最合适的
for the regularization parameter lambda?
正则化参数lambda呢
Just to reiterate, here is our model and here is our learning algorithm subjective.
重申一下 我们的模型和学习参数是这样的
For the setting where we're using regularization, let me define
让我们假设在使用正则化的情形中
j train of theta to be something different
定义Jtrain(θ)为另一种不同的形式
to be the optimization objective
目标同样是最优化
but without the regularization term.
但不使用正则化项
Previously, in earlier video
在先前的授课视频中
when we are not using
当我们没有使用正则化时
regularization, I define j train of theta to
我们定义的Jtrain(θ)
be the same as j of theta as the cost function but
就是代价函数J(θ)
when we are using regularization with this extra lambda term
但当我们使用正则化多出这个lambda项时
we're going to
我们就将训练集误差
define j train my training set error,
也就是Jtrain 定义为
to be just my sum of
训练集数据预测的平方误差的求和
squared errors on the training
或者准确的说
set, or my average squared error
是训练集的平均误差平方和
on the training set without taking into account that regularization chart.
但不考虑正则化项
And similarly, I'm then
与此类似
also going to define the
我们来定义交叉验证集误差
cross-validation set error when the
以及测试集误差
test set error, as before
和之前一样定义为
to be the average sum of squared errors
对交叉验证集和测试集进行预测
on the cross-validation and the test sets.
取平均误差平方和的形式
So just to summarize,
总结一下
my definitions of J train and
我们对于训练误差Jtrain
J C V and J
交叉验证集误差Jcv
Test are just the
和测试集误差Jtest的定义
average squared error, or one
都是平均误差平方和
half of the average
或者准确地说
squared error on my training validation and
是训练集 验证集和测试集进行预测
test sets without the extra
在不使用正则化项时
regularization chart.
平均误差平方和的二分之一
So, this is how we can automatically choose the regularization parameter lambda.
这就是我们自动选取正则化参数lambda的方法
What I usually do is may
通常我的做法是
be have some range of values of lambda I want to try it.
选取一系列我想要尝试的lambda值
So I might be
因此首先我可能考虑
considering not using regularization,
不使用正则化的情形
or here are a few values I might try.
以及一系列我可能会试的值
I might be considering along because
比如说我可能从0.01 0.02
of O1, O2 from O4 and so on.
0.04开始 一直试下去
And you know, I usually step these
通常来讲
up in multiples of
我一般将步长设为2倍速度增长
two until some maybe larger value
一直到一个比较大的值
this in multiples of two you
在本例中以两倍步长递增的话
I actually end up with 10.24;
我们最终取值10.24
it's ten exactly, but you
实际上我们取的是10
know, this is close enough and
但取10已经非常接近了
the 35 decimal
因为小数点后的24
places won't affect your result that much.
对最终的结果不会有太大影响
So, this gives me, maybe
因此 这样我就得到了
twelve different models, that I'm
12个不同的正则化参数lambda
trying to select amongst, corresponding to
对应的12个不同的模型
12 different values of the
我将从这个12个模型中
regularization parameter lambda and of course, you can also go
选出一个最合适的模型，当然了，你也可以试
to values less than 0.01
小于0.01的值
or values larger than 10,
或者大于10的值
but I've just truncated it here for convenience.
但在这里我就不讨论这些情况了
Given each of these 12
得到这12组模型后
models, what we can
接下来
do is then the following:
我们要做的事情是
we take this first
选用第一个模型
model with lambda equals 0,
也就是lambda等于0
and minimize my cos
然后最小化我们的
function j of theta and this
代价函数J(θ)
would give me some parameter vector theta
这样我们就得到了某个参数向量theta
and similar to the earlier video,
与之前视频的做法类似
let me just denote this as
我使用theta上标(1)
theta superscript 1.
来表示第一个参数向量theta
And then I can take my
然后我再取第二个模型
second model, with lambda
也就是
set to 0.01 and
lambda等于0.01的模型
minimize my cos function, now
最小化代价方差
using lambda equals 0.01
当然 现在lambda等于0.01
of course, to get some
那么会得到一个
different parameter vector theta,
完全不同的参数向量theta
we need to know that theta 2,
用theta(2)来表示
and for that I
同理 接下来
end up with theta 3
我会得到theta(3)
so that this is correct for my
这对应于我的第三个模型
third model, and so on,
以此类推
until for for my final model
一直到最后一个
with lambda set to 10,
lambda等于10或10.24的模型
or 10.24, or I end up with this theta 12.
对应theta(12)
Next I can take
接下来我就可以用
all of these hypotheses, all of
所有这些假设
these parameters, and use
所有这些参数
my cross-validation set to evaluate them.
以及交叉验证集来评价它们了
So I can look at my
因此我可以从第一个模型
first model, my second
第二个模型等等开始
model, fits with these different values
对每一个不同的正则化参数lambda
of the regularization parameter and
进行拟合
evaluate them on my cross-validation
然后用交叉验证集来评价每一个模型
set - basically measure the average squared error of each of these parameter
也即测出每一个参数thata在交叉验证集上的
vectors theta on my cross-validation set.
平均误差平方和
And I would then pick whichever one
然后我就选取这12个模型中
of these 12 models gives me
交叉验证集误差最小的
the lowest error on the cross-validation set.
那个模型作为最终选择
And let's say, for the sake
对于本例而言
of this example, that I
假如说
end up picking theta 5,
最终我选择了theta(5)
the fifth order polynomial, because
也就是五次多项式
that has the Noah's cross-validation error.
因为此时的交叉验证集误差最小
Having done that, finally, what
做完这些 最后
I would do if I want
如果我想看看该模型
to report a test set error
在测试集上的表现
is to take the parameter theta
我可以用经过学习
5 that I've
得到的模型theta(5)
selected and look at
来测出它对测试集的
how well it does on my test set.
预测效果如何
And once again here is as
再次重申一下
if we fit this parameter
这里我们依然是用
theta to my cross-validation
交叉验证集来拟合模型
set, which is why I
这也是为什么我之前
am saving aside a separate
预留了一部分数据
test set that I
作为测试集的原因
am going to use to get
这样我就可以用这部分测试集
a better estimate of how
比较准确地估计出
well my a parameter vector
我的参数向量theta
theta will generalize to previously unseen examples.
对于新样本的泛化能力
So that's model selection applied
这就是模型选择在选取
to selecting the regularization parameter
正则化参数lambda时的应用
lambda. The last thing
在这段视频中
I'd like to do in this
我想讲的最后一个问题是
video, is get a
当我们改变
better understanding of how
正则化参数lambda的值时
cross-validation and training error
交叉验证集误差
vary as we as
和训练集误差会随之
we vary the regularization parameter lambda.
发生怎样的变化
And so just a reminder, that
我想提醒一下
was our original cosine function j of
我们最初的代价函数J(θ)
theta, but for this
原来是这样的形式
purpose we're going to define
但在这里我们把训练误差
training error without using
定义为不包括正则化项
the regularization parameter, and cross-validation
交叉验证集误差
error without using the
也定义为不包括
regularization parameter and what I'd like
正则化项
to do is plot this J train
我要做的是
and plot this Jcv, meaning just
绘制出Jtrain和Jcv的曲线
how well does my
随着我增大正则化项参数
hypothesis do for on
lambda的值
the training set and how well
看看我的假设
does my hypothesis do on the
在训练集上的表现如何变化
cross-validation set as I
以及在交叉验证集上
vary my regularization parameter
表现如何变化
lambda so as
就像我们之前看到的
we saw earlier, if lambda
如果正则化项参数
is small, then we're
lambda的值很小
not using much regularization and
那也就是说我们几乎没有使用正则化
we run a larger risk of overfitting.
因此我们有很大可能处于过拟合
Where as if lambda is
而如果lambda的值
large, that is if we
取的很大的时候
were on the right part
也就是说取值在
of this horizontal axis, then
横坐标的右端
with a large value of lambda
那么由于lambda的值很大
we run the high risk of having a bias problem.
我们很有可能处于高偏差的问题
So if you plot J train
所以 如果你画出
and Jcv, what you
Jtrain和Jcv的曲线
find is that for small
你就会发现
values of lambda you can
当lambda的值取得很小时
fit the training set relatively
对训练集的拟合相对较好
well because you're not regularizing.
因为没有使用正则化
So, for small values of
因此 对于lambda值很小的情况
lambda, the regularization term basically
正则化项基本可以忽略
goes away and you're just
你只需要对平方误差
minimizing pretty much your squared error.
做最小化处理即可
So when lambda is small, you
所以当lambda值很小时
end up with a small value
你最终能得到一个
for J train, whereas if
值很小的Jtrain
lambda is large, then you
而如果lambda的值很大时
have a high bias problem and you might not fit your training set so well.
你将处于高偏差问题 不能对训练集很好地拟合
So you end up with a value up there.
因此你的误差值可能位于这个位置
So, J train of
因此 当lambda增大时
theta will tend to
训练集误差Jtrain的值
increase when lambda increases
会趋于上升
because a large value of
因为lambda的值比较大时
lambda corresponds a high bias
对应着高偏差的问题
where you might not even fit your
此时你连训练集都不能很好地拟合
training set well, whereas a
反过来 当lambda的值
small value of lambda corresponds to,
取得很小的时候
if you can you know freely
你的数据能随意地与高次多项式
fit to very high degree polynomials, your data, let's say.
很好地拟合
As for the cross-validation error, we end up with a figure like this.
交叉验证集误差的曲线是这样的
Where, over here on
在曲线的右端
the right, if we
当lambda的值
have a large value of lambda,
取得很大时
we may end up underfitting.
我们会处于欠拟合问题
And so, this is the bias regime
也对应着偏差问题
whereas and cross
那么此时交叉验证集误差
validation error will be
将会很大
high and let me just leave
我写在这里
all that. So, that's Jcv of theta because with
这是交叉验证集误差Jcv
high bias we won't be fitting.
由于高偏差的原因我们不能很好地拟合
We won't be doing well on the cross-validation set.
我们的假设不能在交叉验证集上表现地比较好
Whereas here on the left, this is the high-variance regime.
而曲线的左端对应的是高方差问题
Where if we have two smaller
此时我们的lambda值
value of then we
取得很小很小
may be overfitting the data
因此我们会对数据过度拟合
and so by over fitting the
所以由于过拟合的原因
data then it a cross validation error
交叉验证集误差Jcv
will also be high.
结果也会很大
And so, this is what the
好的 这就是
cross-validation error and what
当我们改变正则化参数
the training error may look
lambda的值时
like on a training set
交叉验证集误差
as we vary the parameter
和训练集误差
lambda, as we vary the regularization parameter lambda.
随之发生的变化
And so, once again, it will
当然 在中间取的某个
often be some intermediate value
lambda的值
of lambda that you know, subsequent just right
表现得刚好合适
or that works best in
这种情况下表现最好
terms of having a small
交叉验证集误差
cross-validation error or a small test set error.
或者测试集误差都很小
And whereas the curves I've drawn
当然由于我在这里画的图
here are somewhat cartoonish and somewhat idealized.
显得太卡通 也太理想化了
So on a real data set
对于真实的数据
the pros you get may
你得到的曲线可能
end up looking a little bit more
比这看起来更凌乱
messy and just a little bit more noisy than this.
会有很多的噪声
For some data sets you will
对某个实际的数据集
really see these poor
你或多或少能看出
source of trends and
像这样的一个趋势
by looking at the plot
通过绘出这条曲线
of the whole or cross validation
通过交叉验证集误差的变化趋势
error, you can either
你可以用自己选择出
manually, automatically try to
或者编写程序自动得出
select a point that minimizes
能使交叉验证集误差
the cross-validation error and
最小的那个点
select the value of lambda corresponding
然后选出那个与之对应的
to low cross-validation error.
参数lambda的值
When I'm trying to pick the
当我在尝试为学习算法
regularization parameter lambda
选择正则化参数
for a learning algorithm, often I
lambda的时候
find that plotting a figure
我通常都会得出
like this one showed here, helps
类似这个图的结果
me understand better what's going
帮助我更好地理解各种情况
on and helps me verify that
同时也帮助我确认
I am indeed picking a good
我选择的正则化参数值
value for the regularization parameter
到底好不好
lambda. So hopefully that
希望这节课的内容
gives you more insight into regularization
让你更深入地理解了正则化
and it's effects on the bias
以及它对学习算法的
and variance of the learning algorithm.
偏差和方差的影响
By know you've seen bias and
到目前为止你已经从不同角度
variance from a lot of different perspectives.
见识了方差和偏差问题
And what I'd like to do
在下一节视频中
in the next video is take
我要做的是
a lot of the insights
基于我们已经浏览过的
that we've gone through and build
所有这些概念
on them to put together
将它们结合起来
a diagnostic that's called learning
建立我们的诊断法
curves, which is a
也称为学习曲线
tool that I often use
这种方法通常被用来
to try to diagnose if a
诊断一个学习算法
learning algorithm may be suffering
到底是处于偏差问题
from a bias problem or a
还是方差问题
variance problem or a little bit of both.
还是两者都有。